- 조이, 오디션 어떻게 됐어?
- 아주 좋았어
- Hey Joey, how'd the audition go?
- Incredible!
감독을 직접 만났는데
누군지 알아?
I met the director this time and you'll never believe who it was.
- 누군데?
- 힌트를 줄게
- Who?
- All right. I'll give you one hint.
워렌 비티야
Warren Beatty.
한 가지 문제가 있는데
Yeah, there's just one thing that might be kind've a problem.
남자랑 키스를 해야 했어
See, I, uh, had to kiss this guy.
그렇게 좋았어?
'Cause he was just so darn cute.
오디션의 배역이
극중에서 키스를 하거든
No, as part of the audition.
See, I'm up for this part of this guy, who the main guy kisses.
넌 배우잖아, 혀 넣고
그냥 해버려야지
Well, hey. You're an actor, I say you just suck it up and do it.
입만 맞추든가
Or you just do it.
키스했어
난 배우잖아
I did do it, I'm a professional.
그런데 뭐가 문제야?
Then what's the problem?
오디션이 끝나고
감독이 내게 이러잖아
See after the scene, Mr. Beatty comes up to me and says
'연기는 좋았는데
키스 실력은 아니군'
'good actor, bad kisser'.
그게 말이나 돼?
내가 키스를 못한다니!
Can you believe that, me not a good kisser,
테레사 수녀님께 박애정신이
없다는 소리나 같아
that's like, like Mother Theresa, not a good mother.
신경 꺼, 워렌 비티가
키스가 뭔지나 알겠어?
Well, come on, who cares what that guy thinks. What does Warren Beatty know about kissing Ooh.
매니저가 뭐래?
Hey, what did your agent say?
키스가 문제라면서
비티가 다시 하라는데
Yep, this kiss thing is defiantly a problem, Mr. Beatty wants to see it again on Monday.
뭐가 문제인지 모르겠어
Man, I gotta figure out what I'm doing wrong.
여자들 중 누가 나한테
키스해 봐
Oh, okay, one of you girls come over here and kiss me.
- 말도 안 돼!
- 택도 없는 소리!
- What, forget it!
- Yeah, right.
친구로서 좀 도와 줘!
Come on, I need your help here.
좋아, 내가 할게
전에도 해봤는데 뭘
All right. I'll do it, I kissed him before I can do it again.
봤지?
친구란 이런 거야
You see this, this is a friend.
하기나 해
Uh-huh, let's go.
잠깐, 껌 좀 뱉고
Oh, wait I have gum.
됐어
Okay.
아주 좋아
강하면서도 부드럽고
Good, very good, firm but tender.
내 친구로 인정할게
I'd recommend you to a friend.
그런데 뭐가 문제란 거지?
Then I don't know what it is. What's the problem?
상대가 남자라서 그런가?
Joey, you know, maybe your just not used to kissing men,
긴장할 수 있잖아
maybe you just tensed up a little,
남자랑 연습해 봐
maybe that's what you need to work on.
그거 말 된다
Yeah, that makes sense.
난 죽어도 못해!
Over my dead body!
난 로스가 죽으면
시체를 방패로 쓸래
And I'll be using his dead body as a shield.
어서 나와
아주 예쁘다니까!
Come on out, honey! I'm telling you look good!
예쁘다고 말해 줘
Tell her she looks good, tell her she looks good.
세상에!
Oh my God,
너무 예뻐!
you look so good!
200명의 하객 앞에서
I can not believe I have to walk down the aisle in front of 200 people
이런 현기증 나는 옷을 입고
입장하라고?
looking like something you drink when your nauseous.
그럼 안 가면 되잖아
전 약혼자의 결혼식인데
So don't,
I don't see why we have to go to this thing anyway, it's your ex-fiancee's wedding.
민디에게 꼭 가겠다고
약속했단 말이야
Because I promised Mindy I would.
배리에겐 결혼한다고
약속했었지
Yeah, well you promised Barry, you'd marry him.
안 갈 수가 없어
내가 들러리란 말이야
Look you guys, I have to go, I'm the Maid-of-Honor.
또 그 사람들을 만나서
And besides you know what I just need
내가 옳은 선택을 했다고
자위하고 싶단 말야
to be in a room again with these people and feel good about myself.
어제 입었던 옷 그대로네
간밤에 역사를 이루었나?
Ooh-oh! Someone's wearing the same clothes they had on last night. Someone get a little action?
- 아마도
- 바람둥이!
- I may have.
- Woo-hoo, stuud!
- 어떻게 생겼어?
- 아직 안 만났어
- What's she look like?
- Well, we haven't exactly met,
밤새도록 인터넷으로
채팅만 했거든
we just stayed up all night talking on the internet.
옴마!
Woo-hoo, geeek!
정말 여자가 맘에 들어
I like this girl, okay, I seriously like this girl,
내가 가끔 본능적으로
빈정대잖아
you now how sometimes I tend get a little defended and quipy...
- 아냐!
- 너 전혀 안 그래
- Get out!
- Nooo!
내게 대놓고 그러잖아
'그만하고 정신차려! '
Well she totally called me on it, okay. She said, 'cut it out, get real',
그래서 정신차렸지
and I did.
그 때 기분이 어땠어?
Wow! What's that like?
지금처럼 이랬어
It's like this,
내 자신을 되찾고
농담도 않고
me, no jokes.
그만 해
괜히 무서워지잖아
All right, stop it, you're freaking me out.
내가 봐도 이상하네
Oh, yeah, I don't like you this way.
- 나중에 보자고
- 잘 가요, 리처드
- All right, I'll see you guys later.
- Bye, Richard.
잘 가요
Bye sweetie,
- 사랑해요
- 나도 사랑해
- I love you.
- I love you, too.
'내 애인 너무 멋져'
I think my boyfriend ever so dreamy,
'우리 결혼식은 어떨까?'
I wonder what our wedding's gonna be like.
무슨 소리야?
결혼식이라니
What are you talking about? What wedding?
결혼에 대한 얘기 안 해?
Come on, like you never talk about that.
안 해, 한 번도 안 했어
Nooo! Never!
우린 이 순간을 즐긴다고
I mean, we're living in the moment.
미래를 잊으니까 좋더라고
God, it is so nice for once to not have to get all hung up on 'Where is this going?'
- 물어 보기 그래?
- 무서울 정도야
- Afraid to ask him?
- Could not be more terrified.
결혼을 심각하게 생각해 봐
Well, I think you should seriously consider the marriage thing,
레이첼이 풍선껌 같은
드레스 입을 기회를 줘야지
give Rachel another chance to dress up like Princess Bubble Yum.
베니가 어디로 갔지?
Where's Benny?
여기 있네!
There he is!
베니가 어디로 갔지?
Where's Benny,
여기 있네!
there he is.
아기가 말을 배우는 것은
Awww! You know that's probably why babies learn to talk,
어른들에게 그만두라고
말해 주기 위해서야
so they can tell grown ups to cut it out.
물어 볼 게 있는데
부담 없이 대답해 줘요
Hey, you know I got a question for ya. Just a little thing, no pressure.
그러지
Okay.
미래에 대해 생각해요?
Did you ever, uh, like, think about the future?
그럼
Sure I do.
나와의 미래요?
Yeah, am I in it?
바로 자기야
Honey, you are it.
오늘 자기 운 텄어요
Oh God, you are about to get sooo lucky.
계속해 봐요
Keep talkin'.
내 면허를 팔고는
Well, uh, sometimes I think about selling my practice,
프랑스로 이주해서
we could move to France,
토스트를 만들어 먹는 거야
make French toast.
프랑스에 가서
Okay, so, uh, we're in France,
토스트를 만들어 먹는데
we're making the toast.
구석에 잠자리도 있나요?
Do you see a little bassinet in the corner?
개집?
Like a hound?
아뇨, 아기가 쓰는 침대요
Not a basset, a bassinet.
아기 침대가 필요해?
You really need the bassinet?
개집에 아기를 재우면
개가 물잖아요
Well, I just think the baby would keep falling off the dog.
우리가 자식을 가지는
생각은 안 해요?
Do you, uh, do you , do you not see kids in our future.
난 아이들을 좋아해
Oh, hey, I love children,
자식도 있고
I have children.
하지만 일흔 살이 돼서
I just don't want to be 70
애들 대학 보내고
여생을 마치기는 싫다고
when our kids go off to college, and our lives can finally start.
난 지금의 자기가 좋아
Look I want you, now.
좋아요
That's Great.
우리 이런 얘기 말아요
You know we don't need to talk about this now.
먼 훗날 얘기잖아요
Really, I mean this is, is so way, way, way, in the future,
고릴라들이 지구를
정복할 시기의 얘기죠
I'm talkin' hovercrafts and apes taking over the planet.
난 이번 배역을 따야 해!
Come on, Chandler, I want this part soo much.
키스 딱 한 번만 하자
비밀로 할게
Just one kiss, I won't tell anyone.
조이, 싫다고 했잖아
Joey, no means no!
죄송하지만 부인
양은 여기 없는데요
I'm sorry we, we don't have your sheep.
내가 보기엔 귀여워
Aww, Rach, I think you look cute
넌...
And you, uh, you,
- 먹어 버릴 수도 있겠어
- 당장 물러서! 싫댔잖아!
- you I could eat with a spoon
- Get away from me I said no!
- 리처드가 밑에 와 있어
- 리처드가 왔어?
- Richard buzzed. He's waiting downstairs.
- Oh, Richard's here.
가서 작별인사 해야지
I should run down say bye to him
잘 다녀와
Bye.
인터넷 애인하곤 어때?
So how's your date with your cyberchick going.
저게 뭐야?
Ooh, hey, what is all that?
홈페이지라는 건데
구겐하임 박물관이야
Oh, it's a website, it's the, uh, the Guggenheim museum.
그녀는 예술을 좋아하고...
See, she likes art,
난 웃긴 단어를 좋아하거든
and I like funny words.
HH가 무슨 뜻이야?
What does she mean by HH?
우리가 손을 잡았다는 뜻이야
It means we're holding hands.
네가 젤 귀여운 남자야?
Are you the cutest?
그런 것 같아
I'm afraid I might just be.
90살 먹은 머리 두 개의
괴물일지도 모르는데
You know, what I think is so great that you are totally into this person
이렇게 빠져들 수 있다니
정말 괜찮은 것 같아
and yet for all you know she could be like 90 years old, or have two heads,
남자일 수도 있고
or. It could be a guy.
남자는 절대 아냐
내가 안다고
Okay, it's not a guy, all right, I know her.
덩치가 커다란 남자
It could be like a big giant guy.
젠장, 이렇게 가까웠는데
모니카가 뒤에서 잡았어
Man, I got this close to him and Monica kneed me in the back.
뭐 해?
What's going on?
챈들러의 여자친구가
여자인지 알아보고 있어
We were just wondering if Chandler's girlfriend is a girl.
얼마나 살 건지 물어 봐
Oh, well. Just ask her how long she's gonna live.
여자들이 남자보다
오래 살잖아
Women live longer than men.
너같이 멍청한 녀석은
정말 첨 봤어
How do you not fall down more?
무슨 피임법을 쓰는지 물어봐
Okay, ask her 'What is her current method of birth control?'
알았어
All right.
'남편이 여비서하고 놀아나요'
"My husband is sleeping with his secretary."
유부녀야?
She's married!
여자인 건 확실하네
Well at least we know she's a woman.
유부녀라니 믿을 수가 없어
I can't believe she's married.
안됐네
Aw, man I'm sorry.
마음이 얼마나 아플까
This must be very tough for ya, huh.
신문에서 읽었는데
쌀을 뿌리면 안 된대요
So, I read this article in the paper the other day that says you're not supposed to throw rice at weddings,
그걸 먹은 비둘기들이
죽거든요
because when pigeons eat rice it kills them.
그래서 초밥 집에 가면
비둘기들이 없군
Oh, that's why you never see pigeons at sushi bars.
- 정말 재밌지?
- 그러게요
- See, we're having fun.
- Oh, absolutely.
우리가 생각 않기로 한 걸
생각하지도 않고 있어요
Yeah, you know I'm not even thinking about that thing that we're not going to be thinking about.
나도 그래
Neither am I.
괜찮아?
Hi, there. Are you all right?
화장실에게 내가 빠져나갔던
창문을 보니까
Yeah, when I was in the bathroom I saw the window that I crawled out of at my wedding,
괜히 왔다는 생각이 들어
and God, I just started thinking that I shouldn't be here, you know I shouldn't,
사람들이 날 보면서
옛날 일을 들먹거리고...
people are going to be looking at me and judging me and, and thinking about the last time.
괜찮을 테니 걱정 마
결혼식이잖아
Sweetie, it's be gonna okay, all right. It's a wedding,
사람들은 신부에게만
신경 쓴다고
generally people focus on the bride.
자기 말이 맞아
God I know, you're right.
좋아요, 모두 여길 보세요!
All rightie, everybody look at me. Good.
신부 들러리들과 파트너는
모두 두 줄로 서 주세요
All right, its time. Bridesmaids and ushers let's see two lines, thank you.
나중에 봐
Okay, I'll see you after the thing.
- 잘해
- 고마워
- Okay, good luck
- Thank you
좋아
Okay, Okay.
왜 말하지 않았어?
Why the hell didn't you tell me!
나도 별수 없었어
I'm sorry. What was I supposed to do
'레이첼, 엉덩이 보여! '
이렇게 소리칠까?
stand up and shout 'Hey, Rachel, your butt is showing!'
창피해 죽겠어
Oh my God this is sooo humiliating.
초등학교 때 전교생들이
모인 자리에서
I think the only thing that tops that was, was,
'코파카바나' 부른 것보다
더 끔찍하다고
was when I was in the eight grade and I had to sing the Copa Cabana in front of the entire school.
단 두 마디 부르고는
난리를 쳤거든
I think I got about two lines into it before I ran and freaked out.
지금도 눈에 선하다고
Oh my God, my entire life is flashing before my eyes.
나도 그 때 기억하는데
그렇게 나쁘지 않았어
Rach, hey look, I remember that, it wasn't so bad.
제발 그만둬, 로스
내 애인이니까 그렇지!
Oh Ross, would you stop, you got me, I'm dating you.
레이첼?
Rachel!
안녕하세요
와인버그 아줌마, 아저씨
Oh hi, Mr. Wineburg, hi Mrs. Wineburg.
이렇게 다시 보니 좋구나
It's so wonderful to see you again, my dear,
그렇게 많이 보기는
기대하지 않았는데
in fact I hardly expected to see so much.
못 봤다고 했잖아요
You told me you didn't see anything.
믿은 당신 잘못이지
I tell ya a lot things!
다시 정상이 된 모습이
보기 좋구나
Well it's wonderful to have you up and about, again, dear.
잘지내렴
Stay well.
저런 말한 사람이
벌써 세 번째야
Okay, now that is the third time someone has said something like that to me today.
레이첼!
Rach! Rach!
- 내가 결혼을 했어!
- 알아
- Oh my God, I'm married!
- I know.
배리 헌터-파버 박사의
부인이 됐다고!
I'm Mrs. Dr. Barry Hunter hyphen Farber.
정말 축하해, 민디
Oh honey, I'm so proud of you, Min.
민디?
Min.
레이첼, 아직 안 갔군
Oh Rach, you're still here,
우리 결혼식엔 사람들이
이 시간에 다 갔거든
at our wedding, they were packing up the chopped liver about now.
그 얘긴 나도 들었어
Yeah, I love that story.
물어 볼 게 있는데
Um, I got a question for you guys.
왜 사람들이 내가 정상으로
보인다고 하는 거지?
Why do people keep is saying that is good to see me up and about?
네가 결혼식에서 도망가자
Well uh, after you ran out on your wedding,
배리가 사람들에게
네가 미쳤다고 했거든
Barry's parents told people that you were sort of....insane.
미쳐?
Insane!
매독에 걸려서
...from the syphilis.
뭐라고?
What?!
그럼 뭐라고 했겠어?
내가 싫어졌다고?
Yeah, what are they gonna say you didn't love me anymore. Come on.
안젤라?
조이 트리비아니예요
Angela? Joey Tribiani.
오늘 밤에 뭐 해요?
Listen, what are ya doing tonight?
그 남자 만나는 건 아는데
함께 나와서...
I know your seeing that guy, I was thinking maybe you could bring him.....
여보세요?
Hello? Hello?
대답 안 할 거야?
벌써 10번째 딩동 거리잖아
Aren't you gonna answer her, that's like the tenth bing-bong message she sent.
- 뭐가 문제인지 알고 싶대
- 뭐가 문제냐고?
- She wants to know what's wrong?
- What's wrong? What's wrong?
당신이 유부녀인 것이
문제라고!
You're married that's what's wrong.
- 이런!
- 왜?
- Oh, my.
- What?
직접 만나고 싶대
She wants to meet you in person.
나도 만나 보고 싶지만
Hey, look, Phoebe I wanted to meet her in person too,
남편이 있는 유부녀라고!
okay, but she's married, she has a husband.
남편이 아니라 네가
그녀의 반쪽이라면?
What if the husband person is the wrong guy, and you are the right guy.
이런 기회가 흔하니?
I mean you don't get chances like this all the time,
이 여자를 이렇게 보내고
여든이 되어서 후회할래?
if you don't meet her now, you're gonna be kicking yourself
축 처진 엉덩이 붙잡고?
when your 80, which is hard to do, and that's how you break a hip.
좋아, 만나겠어
Okay, I'll do it!
잘 생각했어!
Oh, yeah! Okay! Great!
당장 옷 갈아입고 나가서
여자를 만나!
Go, man, go put on your shoes, and, and march out there and meet her!
먼저 샤워부터 하고...
Oh, wait, no, no you have to take a shower, 'cause, eww.
아니, 일단 응답부터 해!
No, you know what you have to answer her, answer her first.
아냐, 너무 긴장되니까
커피부터 만들어
No, no, you know what make some coffee 'cause its too much.
딱 한 번만 더 해요
이번엔 골인시킬게요
Okay, one more, please. Come on, I'm gonna get it in this time, I will.
좋아, 이번이 마지막이야
Okay, last chance.
다시 한번 사과 드려요
Again, I'm sorry.
꼭 자식을 가질 필요는
없을 것 같아요
You know what, maybe I don't need to have children.
사회가 그렇게 생각하게
몰아가는지도 모르죠
You know maybe I just think I do because that is what society,
엄마도 그렇고
and by that I mean my mom,
난 항상 자식에 대해...
has always convinced me that I...
갖고 싶어요
I do,
난 자식을 가져야만 해요
I have to have children, I'm sorry. I just do.
모두 주목해 주세요
Yo! Can I have your attention, please,
베스트맨으로서
축배를 제안합니다
Best Man, making a toast here.
고맙습니다
Thank you.
배리가 레이첼과의
첫 데이트를 하고는...
I remember when Barry got home from his first date with Rachel...
왜?
What?!
똑같은 밴드를 불렀는데
난 똑같은 말 못하니?
What, you hired the same band I can't use the same speech.
고마워요
Thank you, thank you very much.
둘의 행복을 기원합니다
Anyway, I wish you both a wonderful life together.
그리고 레이첼!
And Rachel...
- 왜요?
- 진심으로 말하는데
- What.
- No, no, no now in all seriousness,
다시 돌아온 그 용기에
감탄했어요
its not a lot of women would've had the guts to come back here tonight,
그것도 엉덩이를 드러내놓고
and even fewer, who would do it with their asses hanging out!
저도 한마디하죠
Uh, I like to, uh, to add something to that...
- 대체 뭔 말을 하려고?
- 걱정 말고 앉아 있어
- Why are you adding, why are you adding, why are you adding, why are you adding?
모두 절 모르시겠지만
전 레이첼의 애인인...
Most of you don't know me, I'm Rachel's boyfriend.
하나님 맙소사!
Oh dear God.
로스입니다
Ross,
레이첼은 여기 오는 데
많은 용기를 내야 했어요
uh and uh, I'd just like to say that it did take a lot of courage for Rachel to come here tonight.
진실을 밝히지만
And, uh, for the record
배리를 떠난 이유가
매독이 아니라는 것입니다
she did not run out on Barry because she had syphilis.
심각하게 말하는데 뭐요?
What are you doing I'm serious.
레이첼이 배리를 떠난 것은
사랑하지 않아서죠
Uh, the reason she walked out on, on Barry is simply that she didn't love him,
제 경우엔 다르지만요
which incidentally worked out pretty well for me
건배!
Cheers!
- 주차장에서 봐
- 레이첼!
- See you in the parking lot.
- No, Rach!
또 저렇게 도망가는군요
And once again she is out of here.
누가 9시 45분이죠?
Okay who had 9:45? Um?
좋아, 배리
난 가지 않겠어
Ya, know what Barr, I'm not gonna leave.
가는 게 좋겠지만
그냥 있겠어
I probably should, but I'm not,
네 결혼식에 한 번이라도
끝까지 있기로 했거든
see 'cause I promised myself that I would make it through at least *one* of your weddings.
오늘 밤, 전 여기에 와서
See now, tonight, all I really wanted was
진정 축하하는 마음으로
견디기로 했었어요
to make it though this evening with a little bit of grace and dignity.
한데 말짱 꽝이 됐네요
Well, I guess we can all agree that's not gonna happen.
달리 할 말은 없고...
There's nothing really left to say except....
그녀의 이름은 롤라
그녀는 쇼걸이었네
"Her name was Lola. She was a showgirl.
머리에 노란색 깃털을 꽂고
짧은 드레스를 입었네
With yellow feathers, feathers in her hair, and a dress cut down to there.
그녀는...
She would..."
- 메렝게를 추고
- 고마워, 자기
- Marenge,
- "...marenge, thank you honey,
차차를 추었네
and do the cha-cha.
그녀를 스타를 꿈꾸었고
토니는 바에서 일했네
And while she like to be a star, Tony always tended bar.
잠깐, 모두 불러요!
At the, wait, wait, everybody.."
좋아, 그러겠어
Okay, I'll do it.
뭘요?
You'll do what?
당신과 함께 있으려면
자식을 낳아야 한다며
If kids is what I takes to be with you then kids it is.
세상에...
Oh my God!
다시 할 수 있다고
If I have to I'll, I'll do all again,
오후 4시에 간식 먹이고
I'll do the 4 o'clock feeding thing,
학교육성회에도 나가고
I'll go to the P.T.A. meetings,
축구팀 코치도 하고
I'll coach the soccer team.
- 정말이에요?
- 그래야만 한다면
- Really?
- Yeah, if I have to.
모니카...
Monica,
난 자기를 잃기 싫어
I don't wanna lose you,
다시 해야만 한다면
그럴 거라고
so if I have to do it all over again, then I will.
당신은 좋은 사람이에요
You're the most wonderful man.
'그래야만 한다면'이란 말을
반복하지만 않았다면
And if you hadn't of said 'if I have to' like seventeen times,
당장 그러자고 했겠지만...
then I'd be saying 'okay, let's do it.'
그런데 아니군
But you're not.
세상에...
Oh my God,
내가 이런 말을 하게
될 줄은 몰랐는데
I can't believe what I'm getting ready to say.
난 아기를 갖고 싶어요
I wanna have a baby,
하지만 당신이 진심으로
원하지 않는다면 싫어요
but I don't wanna have one with someone who doesn't really wanna have one.
정말...
God.
사랑해
I love you.
알아요
I know you do.
저도 사랑해요
Me too.
이제 어쩌죠?
So what now?
글쎄...
I guess we just
계속 춤을 춰야겠지
keep dancing.
어디 있어?
Where is she, Where is she?
잠깐, 물어 볼 게 있는데
그 여자 어디 있지?
Oh, hey, I have a question, where is she?
진정해, 챈들러
나올 테니까 걱정 마
Chandler, relax, Chandler, she'll be here.
저 여자야!
Ooh, oh, oh, that's her.
인생이 애들 장난이니?
Yeah, 'cause life's just that kind.
문 좀 그만 쳐다봐
꼭 무슨 주전자 같잖아
Chandler, you gotta stop staring at the door. It's like a watched pot,
그렇게 뚫어져라 쳐다보면
절대 안 끓는다고
you know if you keep looking at it then the door is to, never gonna boil.
내 생각으로는 네가...
I think what you have to do is try not to...
맙소사!
Oh my God!
오... 마이... 갓!
OH.....MY.....GAWD!!
OH.....MY.....GOD!!
친구로서 죄책감 생겨서
도저히 안 되겠어
All right I've been feeling incredibly guilty about this,
난 좋은 친구란 말야
아무 말 말고 눈감아
because I wanna be a good friend, and dammit I am a good friend. So just, just shut up and close your eyes.
넌 정말 좋은 친구야
Wow, you are a good friend,
아침에 오디션 있었는데
나 떨어졌어
'course the audition was this morning, and I didn't get it.
그런데 너 키스 잘한다
But that was a hell of a kiss.
레이첼은 복도 많지
Rachel is a very lucky girl.